Rubinow, Isaac Max Papers 5616
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Lorwin, Lewis L. - Chairman, National Economic and Social Planning Association, 1931-1935 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  re article for Plan Age by Rubinow; discusses report on Jewish migration - Peru
- Lu, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Lubin, Isadore - Commissioner of Labor Statistics, U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1932-1935 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  re study by Rubinow on old age pensions and other routine literary correspondence
- Lundeen Bill, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  correspondence with E.M. Lundeen, Congressman; mss. re the Bill, article in the Survey
- Lurie, Harry L. - Director Bureau of Jewish Social Research, 1931-1936 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  re conference plans and other Bureau activities; correspondence re Wagner-Lewis and Lundeen Bills
- Ly, 1927-1935 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Mac-Man, 1902-1935 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  (1902) letter from U.S. Census Office re 12th census statistics; routine literary; correspondence re German situation with Amy G. Maher, President Toledo Consumer's League
- Magnusson, Leifur - Director, International Labor Organization, Washington Office, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  re social insurance
- Mai-Mai, 1925-1933 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  routine personal, mostly-with Leon A. Malkiel, close friend and attorney
- Man, 1927-1935 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Map-Mar, 1920-1933 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Marx Institute of America - with Morris Zucker, Secretary, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  literary correspondence re Rubinow's socialism pamphlet and discusses Socialist movement
- Mas, 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  correspondence, personal and routine
- Mat-Maz, 1923-1936 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Mayfair Manor Investments, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  personal/financial
- Me, 1925-1936 (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Me, 1923-1936 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  personal, literary, letter to S.M. Melamed, Editor of the Reflex re his editorial on "Loverly Hadassah," (1928)
- Menorah Journal, 1926-1931 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- Mi, 1902-1936 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  correspondence with United Mine Workers President John Mitchell (1902) re study of wages and hours and a check for payment; correspondence with Justin Miller, Department of Justice re study of crime prevention (1936); with Militant Liberal Movement (1933) re Congress meeting; and routine
- Mo, 1921-1935 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  literary, routine and personal
- Mu, 1927-1935 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  literary correspondence; J. Prentice Murphy, Children's Bureau of Philadelphia re literary works
- Municipal Court Committee (Philadelphia), 1924-1927 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  Committee to Study Court's activities
- Na, 1917-1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Nation, 1925-1933 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  literary correspondence re socialized medicine, NRA, unemployment insurance and divorce
- National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1912-1914 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  2 letters re Rubinow contributing to a symposium on segregation and Civil Rights Act violations in places of public accommodations
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  meeting announcement and constitution
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service - Rubinow, Executive Committee member of the Conference, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  correspondence re serving on Immigration Commission and routine organizational activities with various officer's including George W. Rabinoff, Secretary
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Includes agenda, correspondence re resolutions and routine
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  Includes program, financial statement, minutes, lists of members, correspondence re work of Committee on the Status of a Social Worker; correspondence re plans for annual conference and routine
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 9-12)
  Includes copies of program; routine correspondence re activities of committees and the organization
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service (Freund) -Michael Freund, Secretary, National Conference, 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
  includes minutes, form letters, correspondence re meetings of various committees, literary and routine
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service (Rabinoff) -George W. Rabinoff, Executive Director and Secretary of National Conference, 1931- 1936 (Box 6, Folder 18-20)
  re routine
- National Conference of Jewish Social Service (Taylor) -Maurice Taylor, Chairman, Committee on the Status of the Jewish Social Worker, 1932- 1936 (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
  re questionnaire sent out to find out where Jews are practicing social work; economic security for social workers; routine literary correspondence
- National Conference of Social Work, 1931-1936 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Includes bulletin, handbook, notes and correspondence re meetings, plans for annual conference, etc.
- Ne, 1914-1929 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Correspondence with Richard Neustadt, Secretary, NYS Committee on Relief for Widowed Mothers (l9lU) re comparison of widows' pension laws in various states; correspondence re Dependency Index (1918) with various state agencies; re Civil Service exam for Chief of Claim Department (NYS) 1918 concerning Rubinow's eligibility; literary with NY Times (1928) and routine
- Neg-Neu - Negro Civic Welfare Association, 1931-1936 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  re Rubinow attending meeting re Negro work; correspondence re Emanuel Neumann re World Zionist Executive appointment and personal
- Nevada, State of, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  re Rubinow's work as consulting Actuary of Nevada Industrial Commission
- New, 1931-1935 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  correspondence with editor of New Leader, New York Herald Tribune, New York Times re articles and personal
- New Masses, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  literary correspondence with editor on Rubinow's article in form of a debate, "The Case Against H.R. 7598" which criticizes the Lundeen Bill and correspondence re Mary VanKleek defending the Bill; also letter re David Ramsey's review of Rubinow's book, "Quest for Security"
- New Republic, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  correspondence re articles by Rubinow on old age and routine literary
- New Republic (Bruce Bliven), 1930-1934 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  correspondence with Bliven, editor re Rubinow's articles on Divorce and Marriage, unemployment and routine
- New York Association for Labor Legislation, 1912-1913 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  re Rubinow's election to Executive Committee of the Association and routine
- New York City Department of Health, 1914-1915 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  correspondence re requesting Rubinow to serve on Committee on Records of the Department and routine activities
- New York City Department of Public Charities, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  correspondent re Rubinow's availability to serve as Secretary of Actuary of the Social Insurance Commission; his work as Director of Bureau of Social Statistics, discusses various studies in progress
- Ni, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  correspondence with Henry Niles, Actuary re article by Abraham Epstein criticizing life insurance companies
- Niebyl, K.H., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- No, 1907-1935 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  correspondence re lectures; with George W. Norris, U.S. Senator re Birth Control Bill (1932); personal, financial; North American Review re Rubinow's article "The Price of Speed"
- O, 1910-1935 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  correspondence with Mary W. Ovington re causes of Negro death rate (1910); personal; correspondence re Ohio unemployment insurance; routine literary; correspondence re Sabin Orgler (friend of Raymond Rubinow) re his ideas of starting a religious revival movement among Jewish youth
- Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corporation, 1911-1916 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Includes official agreement of employment 1911; letter of resignation of position as chief statistician, March 1916; correspondence with prospective employers
- Old Age, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Includes tabulation sheets, charts re care of aged in Hamilton County
- Old Age (Berrodin) - H.J. Berrodin, Chief, Division of Aid for the Aged, Department of Public Welfare, Columbus, Ohio, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  re cost of institution care, funerals,-private and public home care, legal opinion (interpretation of) granting aid to the aged, applications for aid
- Old Age (Clippings), 1934 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  clippings from Cincinnati newspapers re old age
- Old Age (Edwards, Ada), 1935 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  with Edwards, General Supervisor, Federal Emergency Relief Administration in Ohio,
- Old Age (Gillett, Laurence), 1935 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  re funeral benefits, costs
- Old Age (Hinriches, A.F.), 1935 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  with U.S.B.L.S. re plan for a study of old age in Cincinnati
- Old Age (Statistics) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  statistical data on old age in Ohio, n.d.
- Old Age (Swing, F.) - Frederick Swing, County Commissioner, Hamilton County, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  re RuMnow's resignation as member of Advisory Committee to the Board of County Commissioners for the Aid of the Aged for Hamilton County, because of unwillingness of state to cooperate with the committee and other routine
- Old Age Conference, 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  includes correspondence, program re the conference, "The Care of the Aged - Proceedings of the Deutsch Foundation Conference, 1930"
- Old Age Pension (Ach, Samuel) - Ach, President Hamilton County Commissioners, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  re Negro serving on Advisory Committee for Old Age Pensions, financial and other activities of the Committee
- Old Age Pension (Alexander, E.F.) - member of Advisory Committee, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  re meeting arrangements
- Old Age Pension (Brown, M.L.) - Brown, Chief, Division of Aid for the Aged, Department of Public Welfare, Columbus, Ohio, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  re funeral costs, publicity, revision of forms and routine
- Old Age Pensions (Circulars and Instructions), 1934 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  includes publications, information bulletin, instructions for investigators and clerks for Hamilton County, Ohio
- Old Age Pensions (Cleveland, M.S.) - Marion S. Cleveland, Supervisor, Hamilton County Board, Division of Aid for Aged, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  re various cases and routine
- Old Age Pensions (forms and circular letters), 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  forms circular letters, correspondence re Hamilton County Advisory Board
- Old Age Pensions (laws), 1934 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  publications, memos
- Old Age Pensions (members of board), 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  lists of members serving on Committee for the Administration of Old Age Pension Law in Hamilton County and miscellaneous correspondence
- Old Age Pensions (miscellaneous correspondence), 1934 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  correspondence, studies, questionnaires
- Old Age Pensions - (minutes), 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  minutes of meetings of County Board of Division of Aid for the Aged, 5/ll/31+-8/19/35
- Old Age Pensions (monthly reports), 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  monthly statistical reports for Hamilton County, Ohio, Division of Aid for the Aged
- Old Age Pensions (Wagner, M.) - Margaret Wagner, Executive Secretary, Benjamin Rose Institute, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  re comparison of figures between Cleveland and Cincinnati
- Organizing - Jewish Community (Box 7, Folder 26)
  typewritten notes on cards, n.d.
- Osborn, Henry F. - Resident American Museum of Natural History, Professor, 1895-1913 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  re writing a preface to Russian edition of Neo Lamarckian School; Rubinow's days at Columbia studying biology
- Pa, 1911-1935 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  routine and personal
- Palestine - Outline of "Reconstruction of Palestine and It's Problems", 1929 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Pe, 1915-1936 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  letters recommending Rubinow as Manager of State Fund in Pennsylvania (1915); re assisting in writing a platform on social insurance for People's Council of America; correspondence with People's Lobby
- Pennsylvania - Pennsylvania Health Insurance Commission, 1918-1935 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  correspondence re routine and Pennsylvania Conference on Social Welfare routine correspondence
- Pennsylvania, University of, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  correspondence with William Draper Lewis, University of Pennsylvania Law School re activities of the Committee on Health Insurance Commission
- People's Bank, 1930-1935 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- People's Institute, 1911-1912 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  request for Rubinow to speak at a program re workmen's compensation and routine literary correspondence
- Perkins, Frances, 1932-1934 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  correspondence with Miss Perkins (Secretary of Labor (193*0 and NYS Industrial Commissioner (1932-33) re unemployment insurance; includes letter inviting Rubinow to Washington to National Conference on Economic Security and his acceptance; also invitation letter to Rubinow to meet with William Beveridge, Director of London School of Economics re unemployment insurance
- Perlman, Selig, 1931-1936 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Pf-Ph, 1931-1935 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  correspondence re various Philadelphia meetings; with Herbert E. Phillips re California State health insurance
- Pi, 1915-1933 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  correspondence with A.J. Pillsbury, Chairman, Industrial Accident Commission re Rubinow's employment with the Commission (1915) and routine
- Pinchot, Gifford - Governor of Pennsylvania, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  re Rubinow sending report of Ohio Unemployment Insurance Commission to him and his interest in unemployment insurance for the state of Pennsylvania and Pinchot's' reply
- Pittsburgh, Pa., 1932-1935 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  correspondence re various speeches and meetings in Pittsburgh; correspondence with Dr. H.A. Shaw (Pittsburgh) re speaking engagements re health insurance to medical groups and personnel
- Plan Age, 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  publication of National Economic and Social Planning Association of which Rubinow was a member, routine correspondence
- Po, 1913-1935 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  letter from Thomas R. Powell, Acting Editor, Political Science Quarterly (1913) re turning Rubinow's offer to submit to the Quarterly a criticism of Simkhovitch's book on Marxism; personal correspondence; correspondence with David deSolaPool re financial problems with Sharah Zedek Hospital and personal; routine
- Pr, 1905-1936 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  (1905) handwritten letters from sister-in-law?; A. Press re personal; correspondence with George Price, Chairman, Executive Committee Joint Board of Sanitary Control re social insurance; personal financial and routine
- Pu, 1917-1936 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Public Health Federation - Rubinow, member of Coordinating Committee of the Federation (Cincinnati), 1930-1936 (Box 7, Folder 45-47)
  form letters, programs, meeting announcements, correspondence re Negro death rate, transients, medical costs and many other subjects
- Publishers, 1902-1935 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  correspondence re literary writings with Charles H. Kerr & Co. re translation of "American Farmer," Economic Aspect of the Negro Problem; Wilshire's Magazine, Leo Wise and Co.; Doubleday Page & Co.; Spectator Co.; Yale Review; Encyclopedia of the Negro Race; Jewish Encyclopedia; McClure's Magazine; Macmillan Co.; Chronicle Co. Ltd.; Sturgis and Walton Co.; The Outlook; B.W. Heubsch; Modern Hospital; NY Tribune; NY Times; the New Republic; North American Review
- Q, 1931-1934 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Quest for Security, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  correspondence re review of Rubinow's book, congratulations, lists of persons receiving copies, clippings and announcements
- Ra-Ran, 1930-1935 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Rabinoff, Max, 1911-1913 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Rager, Fritz, 1933-1935 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  personal correspondence, discusses conditions in Austria and other parts of Europe and social insurance re Rager emigrating to the U.S. and finding government employment
- Rand School of Social Science, 1911-1931 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  correspondence re Rubinow teaching courses and routine
- Rap, 1925-1926 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  family correspondence
- Rat-Raz, 1926-1936 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  correspondence with Nathan Ratnoff, Chairman, Hebrew University Hospital Fund for Palestine re fund raising for the establishment of hospitals in Palestine; personal
- Re, 1927-1935 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  correspondence re Reconstruction Finance Corporation Rubinow testifying before U.S. Senate Committee on Manufacturers on the unemployment relief situation in Ohio; personal and routine
- Recreation Commission, Chicago, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  1st annual report
- Reed, Ellery - Director, Helen S. Trounstir^ Foundation and Legislative Committee Chairman, Community Chest, Cincinnati, 1930-1936 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  re legislation concerning transients relief
- Rh-Ri, 1927-1936 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Rob-Ron (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Roosevelt, Mrs. Franklin D., 1934 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  letter to Mrs. Roosevelt re his book "Quest for Security" pointing out certain chapters of interest to President and Mrs. Roosevelt
- Ror-Rot, 1927-1936 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Rosanoff, M.A. - Head Chemistry Department, Clark University, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  one letter re Mr. Yanovsky, a chemist requesting help in obtaining a position in the U.S.
- Rosen, Ben - Director, Associated Talmud Torahs of Philadelphia, 1931-1935 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  correspondence re Jewish population study and literary
- Rosenberg, Martin, 1895-1896 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  handwritten personal correspondence from Berlin and Paris
- Rosenwald, Lessing, 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  re unemployment insurance including a 7 page letter from Rubinow re fundamentals of the theory of unemployment insurance
- Ross, Edward A. - Professor, Department of Political Economy, Univ. of Wisconsin, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  re Rubinow participating in a program for American Sociological Association
- Rothenberg, Morris, 1928-1929 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  personal correspondence re Hadassah
- Rowe, E (Box 8, Folder 22)
  personal, n.d.
- Ru, 1895-1934 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  correspondence with Ellen Rugg re domestic employment; correspondence with Meigs Russell, Field Secretary with American Association for Old Age Security re their common interests and routine
- Rubenstein, Frank J. - Executive Director, Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Rubin, Samuel A. - Manager, Talmudical Encyclopedia Publishers, 1931-1933 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  re literary
- Rubinoff, David and Philip, 1932-1935 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  cousins of Rubinow involved in entertainment business (music) routine personal correspondence
- Rubinoff, Joshua, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  personal correspondence with Rubinow's brother, a dentist in NYC
- Rubinoff, Violet, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  personal correspondence with niece
- Rubinow, David, 1925-1935 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Rubinow, Doris, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Rubinow, Edward, 1930-1931 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  personal correspondence with nephew,
- Rubinow, Ethel, 1925-1931 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  personal correspondence with cousin
- Rubinow, Fannie, 1930-1934 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Rubinow, George, 1925-1934 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  routine personal correspondence
- Rubinow, Isabelle, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Rubinow, Isaac M., 1925-1935 (Box 8, Folder 36-39)
  personal family correspondence; 3 page letter to Morris Waldman re meeting in Washington (1933) with Congressmen discusses Deutsch's speech, American Jewish Congress, personal issues; addresses by Rubinow; clippings on Rubinow's appointment as Executive Director of Brooklyn Federation of Jewish Charities; correspondence re Rubinow's manuscript "Some Statistical Aspects of Marriage and Divorce"
- Rubinow, I.M. (Box 8, Folder 40)
  Biographies n.d.
- Rubinow, I.M., 1935 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  60th birthday - birthday wishes
- Rubinow, I.M., 1929-1935 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  Miscellaneous reports, charts, memorandums
- Rubinow, Laura, 1930-1936 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  personal correspondence with daughter
- Rubinow, Leonora, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 44)
- Rubinow, Olga, 1930-1936 (Box 8, Folder 45-47)
  personal correspondence with daughter, also literary correspondence and articles
- Rubinow, Olga - Employment Record, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  contains correspondence and resume of daughter's
- Rubinow, Raymond, 1929-1936 (Box 8, Folder 49-51)
  with Rubinow's son re Julius Rosenwald Fund who was Secretary of Philanthropic Affairs; personal and professional correspondence
- Rubinow, Saul, 1924-1936 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  Rubinow's brother, a physician, correspondent re medical and hospital costs, personal and financial
- Rubinow, Sidney, 1927-1935 (Box 8, Folder 53-54)
  correspondence re activities of American Farm Bureau Federation of which S. Rubinow was involved, and personal
- Rubinow, Sidney Jr., 1931-1934 (Box 8, Folder 55)
- Sa, 1917-1935 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  correspondence with Moses Salzer, A.L. Sacher, Ira Sanders, Aaron Sapiro, re routine
- Saffrin, Sadie, 1930-1934 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  re literary correspondence (statistician with Jewish Welfare Society) and Society activities
- Sage (Russell) Foundation, 1929-1936 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  routine and literary
- Salkind, Alexander - Acting Director, Hadassah Medical Organization, 1923-1925 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  re appointing a new Director and routine
- Sc, 1923-1935 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  correspondence with Claude E. Scattergood re plan for Sears and Roebuck to sell life insurance; Alexander L. Schwartz, Edwin J. Schanfarber, Alfred Schumann, Arch D. Schultz, Clement Schwinges, Harry Schneiderman re unemployment insurance, statistics and routine
- Schneider, David M., 1930-1935 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  with NYS Department of Social Welfare, correspondence re old age statistics (NYS), personal and routine
- Schreiber, Emma - with Bureau of Jewish Social Research, 1929-1933 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  re Jewish social work in general and personal
- Schreiber, Nettie, 1934-1935 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  letter of recommendation to National Recovery Administration; personal correspondence re securing a position in Washington
- Se, 1918-1934 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  with Peter Segal re socializing dentistry; with Clarence Senior, Socialist Party re Workers Rights Amendment, asking for Rubinow's opinion; Max Senior re circular on tuberculosis
- Seager, Henry, 1910-1928 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  routine literary correspondence, arrangement of lectures for Rubinow at Columbia University and routine
- Selekman, Benjamin M. - Director, Associated Jewish Philanthropies, Chairman Committee on Social Policy of National Conference of Jewish Social Service, 1932-1936 (Box 9, Folder 11-13)
  re old age movement in Missouri, assisting Epstein in raising funds; committee activities in general; re cooperation with other interested agencies working towards same social legislative goals
- Seligman, Edwin, 1903-1931 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  correspondence re Rubinow's work toward his PhD degree at Columbia and his employment with U.S. Civil Service Commission
- Sellin, Thorsten - (Editor, Annals), 1931-1933 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Seman, Philip - General Director, Jewish People's Institute, 1930-1936 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  re routine literary and personal
- Senior, Leon - Examiner, NYS Insurance Department, 1912-1918 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  correspondence re cost of workmen's compensation in the U.S.
- Service Bureau for Education in Human Relations, 1932-1936 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  report, suggested programs, estimated budget
- Sh, 1905-1936 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Shankman, Ann, 1932-1935 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Shimkin, N. - Hadassah Medical Organization, 1923-1926 (Box 9, Folder 21)